<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Viktor&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://vashirov.blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Viktor&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 11:07:01 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vashirov.blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Running Pi-hole in a rootless container using podman</title>
      <link>https://vashirov.blog/2021/10/08/running-pi-hole-in-a-rootless-container-using-podman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 11:07:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vashirov.blog/2021/10/08/running-pi-hole-in-a-rootless-container-using-podman/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Pi-hole is a network-wide advertisement and tracker blocker. It&amp;rsquo;s a DNS sinkhole for your home network. I&amp;rsquo;ve been running it for several years now on my Raspberry Pi 3. Recently my SD card died and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a replacement at hand. So I decided to move Pi-hole to my fanless Intel NUC that I already use to host several services in my home network.
Here&amp;rsquo;s my log of configuring it with all the problems that I encountered along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Let’s Encrypt certificates in OpenShift</title>
      <link>https://vashirov.blog/2021/10/04/installing-lets-encrypt-certificates-in-openshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 16:11:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vashirov.blog/2021/10/04/installing-lets-encrypt-certificates-in-openshift/</guid>
      <description>Introduction At my homelab I deploy and destroy OpenShift clusters several times a day. One of the most annoying things for me is accessing OpenShift console when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have proper certificates installed: browser warns about self-signed certificates and makes me do several clicks first in order to access the UI. And of course, in real-life deployments you have to use proper certificates to secure routes and API endpoints.
These days it&amp;rsquo;s easy to obtain free TLS certificates using Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt or similar services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to enable shell auto completion for OpenShift `oc` command</title>
      <link>https://vashirov.blog/2021/04/10/how-to-enable-shell-auto-completion-for-openshift-oc-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vashirov.blog/2021/04/10/how-to-enable-shell-auto-completion-for-openshift-oc-command/</guid>
      <description>I was pleasantly surprised to find out that oc (and kubectl too) has a built-in capability to generate shell auto completion.
For Zsh add the following snippet to your ~/.zshrc:
if [ $commands[oc] ]; then source &amp;lt;(oc completion zsh) fi For Bash add this to ~/.bashrc:
if command -v oc &amp;amp;&amp;gt;/dev/null; then source &amp;lt;(oc completion bash) fi After opening a new shell:
$ oc &amp;lt;TAB&amp;gt; adm describe logout replace annotate diff logs rollback api-resources edit new-app rollout api-versions ex new-build rsh apply exec new-project rsync attach explain observe run auth expose options scale autoscale extract patch secrets cancel-build get plugin serviceaccounts cluster-info help policy set completion idle port-forward start-build config image process status cp import-image project tag create kustomize projects version debug label proxy wait delete login registry whoami </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>https://vashirov.blog/1970/01/01/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vashirov.blog/1970/01/01/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>👋 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
